感谢以下大佬于2020年4月份的赞助：
背景素材出处：youtu.be/zfvJDllNjlY，SciNews，The first Soyuz-2.1a is ready to launch Soyuz MS-16，20200406
背景音乐：08 Rollout-Test Shot Starfish 出处：testshotstarfish.com
音乐授权说明：reddit.com/r/SpaceXMasterrace/comments/bl8ysl/all_of_the_streams_on_the_channel_have_been_ended/ena07xn
2020年4月世界航天发射统计
总计：5次（失败1次）
2020年世界航天发射统计（截止4月30日）
总计：29次（失败3次）
国家：俄罗斯
时间：2020/4/9 08:05:06(UTC)
位置：拜科努尔31/6号工位
有效载荷：联盟MS-16飞船
有效载荷质量：7.28吨
载具：联盟-2.1a
轨道：国际空间站近地轨道
提供商&客户：俄罗斯航天集团
数据来源：英文维基Soyuz MS-16
结果：成功
备注：这是联盟2.1a首次发射载人飞船
素材出处：youtu.be/t7Ld_b1pvSY，SciNews，
Soyuz-2.1a launches Soyuz MS-16，20200409
第二个塔架也撤离了 现在距离发射还有15秒
There goes the second tower so we are 15 seconds away from launch.
我们将会看到助推器的底部亮起来
We're gonna see the boosters at the bottom light up.
并且随着它们的推力的增加 最终超过了(火箭的重力)
And as their thrust builds that eventually over come.
Made one.
起飞
And liftoff.
Cassidy, Ivanishin and Vagner开始了他们前往国际空间站的旅途
Cassidy, Ivanishin and Vagner on their way to the International Space.
2级火箭分离确认
We confirm separation of stage 2.
火箭状态正常
We'll see it as well everything's nominal on board.
收到
Copy.
那么我们会看到发动机关闭
So we'll see the engines cut off
一旦三级火箭分离时 它会让乘员感到一点颠簸
and once the vehicle separates it usually gives the crew a bit of a jolt.
然后联盟飞船就失重了
Then the Soyuz will be flying free.
我们能看到三级火箭分离了
We see the third stage separating there.
你能看到它正在离开
You can see it dropping away now.
三级火箭分离确认
Third stage separation confirmed.
恭喜你们
Congratulations guys.
你们入轨了
You are in orbit.
我把你们移交给莫斯科任务控制中心吧
I am handing you over to the Mission Control Moscow.
正如我们在视频中看到的那样 太阳能帆板展开
As we can see on the video here, that solar array deployed.
另外一边的太阳能帆板也确认展开了
We have confirmation that one on the other side also deployed.
还有一些附件 比如所有交会使用的天线
Along with what's known as the appendages all of the antennas of the rendezvous
通信的天线 都在联盟飞船上展开了
and the communication antennas all deployed on the Soyuz spacecraft.
国家：中国
时间：2020/4/9 19:46(UTC+8)
位置：西昌卫星发射中心LC-2
有效载荷：Palapa-N1
有效载荷质量：5.55吨
载具：长征三号乙
轨道：GTO(同步转移轨道)
提供商：长城公司
客户：印尼PSNS公司
数据来源：航天爱好者网(b23.tv/BV1XC4y1p7va)
结果：失利
备注：三级问题
素材出处：weibo.com/3279752321/ICyuwDWvi，
9ifly.cn/thread-89280-14-1.html
国家：伊朗
时间：2020/4/22 03:59(UTC)
位置：沙赫鲁德导弹测试场
有效载荷：Noor 1
有效载荷质量：小于50kg
载具：Qased
轨道：426 km x 444 km x 59.8°(近地轨道)
运营方：伊斯兰革命卫队
数据来源：英文维基Qased (rocket)，Noor (satellite)
结果：成功
备注：伊朗发射的第一颗军事卫星，
是一颗光学遥感的立方星
素材出处：youtu.be/vkq-o555gYI，20200423
youtu.be/Kd5iWNpmUbU，SciNews，
Qased launches Noor satellite，20200422
2, 1, 0
国家：美国
时间：2020/4/22 19:30:30(UTC)
位置：肯尼迪航天中心39号A发射复合体
(Kennedy LC-39A)
提供商&客户：SpaceX
有效载荷：60颗星链(Starlink)卫星
有效载荷质量：15.6吨
载具：猎鹰9号Block 5(B1051)
轨道：53° LEO(低于550km)
结果：成功
素材出处：
youtu.be/wSge0I7pwFI，
SpaceX，Starlink Mission，20200422
双语字幕版b23.tv/BV1Pz411z71z
备注：上次海上回收失败原因找到，
残留清洁剂引燃影响传感器造成计算机误判，
这次海上回收成功，是B1051的第四次发射
速度          高度
二级遥测数据
点火 起飞
Ignition, liftoff.
起飞
猎鹰9号的固定夹具释放
飞行过程开始
猎鹰9号程序转弯
Falcon 9's pitching downrange.
最大气动压力
Maximum aerodynamic pressure.
Max-Q
最大气动压力 - 这是火箭
(在上升段)受到的最大气动压力
接下来一分钟内会连续发生三件事
Now coming up in about a minute we will have
three events happening back to back.
首先是一级发动机关机或者说MECO
First is main engine cutoff or MECO.
这是指9台梅林1D发动机关闭来让火箭减速
This is where all nine M-1D engines will shut off to slow the vehicle down
为了分级 也就是第二件事
in preparation for the second event which is stage separation.
分级是指一二级分离
This is where the second stage will separate from the first stage
而一级会返回地球着陆
with stage one making its way back down to earth for landing
二级则开始进行我前面说的第三件事
and stage two kicking off that third event that I mentioned
这就是二级发动机第一次开机
which is SES-1
一二级分离确认
Stage separation confirmed.
分级
一级从二级上分离
一级发动机成功关机
Successful MECO.
一二级成功分离
Successful stage sep.
看起来二级火箭发动机也点火了 也就是SES-1
And it appears we have reignited or ignited that second stage engine for SES-1.
SES-1
二级发动机
第一次点火
抛整流罩
火箭顶部的保护性鼻锥
被抛离
整流罩分离确认
Fairing separation confirmed.
整流罩分离成功
And we have fairing separation.
我们成功重复使用了这个整流罩
We have successfully reuse this fairing
现在这两半开始返回并准备溅落
and now those halves and making their way back down to the sea
我们希望能把它们擓(kuǎi)出来
where hopefully we can scoop them up.
一级火箭着陆腿展开
Stage 1 landing leg deploy.
二级火箭FDS(飞行动力系统)良好
Stage 2 FDS(flight dynamics system) safe.
它来了
There it is.
让我们看看
Let's see.
我们听到了欢呼声
We have cheers.
我们看到了火箭
We have a rocket.
它们这就分离了
There they go.
好吧 这就是那60颗星链卫星
All right that's those 60 Starlink satellites.
起飞
and liftoff
国家：俄罗斯
时间：2020/4/25 01:51:41(UTC)
位置：拜科努尔31/6号工位
有效载荷：进步MS-14飞船
有效载荷质量：7.02吨
载具：联盟-2.1a
轨道：国际空间站近地轨道
提供商&客户：俄罗斯航天集团
数据来源：www.nextspaceflight.com
/launches/details/906
结果：成功
备注：为纪念卫国战争75周年，
火箭有着卫国战争勋章的标志
素材出处：youtu.be/TFZWjAz4SVk，SciNews，
Progress MS-14 launch，20200409
第75个进步补给飞船起飞 它将入轨并进行与国际空间站的快速对接
liftoff of the 75th progress resupply ship on a fast-track to orbit flight to the International Space Station.
一级火箭发动机关闭
And we have first stage shutdown.
二级发动机工作正常
Second stage engines' up and running in good shape.
背景音乐：Nihilore - Earth，出处：www.nihilore.com，音乐许可：CC BY 4.0
三级火箭发动机关闭
And we have 3rd stage shutdown.
然后分离
And separation.
下一件事是展开进步飞船的太阳能帆板和导航天线
Next event will be the deployment of the progress's solar arrays and navigational antennas.
你能看到这些事情现在都在进行
And you see that function now in work.
所有附件都展开了
And all of the appendages have now been deployed.
进步飞船上的太阳能帆板 导航天线还有摄像支架都展开了
The solar arrays, the navigational antennas and the TV boom on the progress.
一次完美的发射 进入了预订的轨道
A perfect launch and a perfect ride to its preliminary orbit.